These atoms are eternal and unchanging, and exist in an infinite number.
When a thing is dissolved, the atoms will form new things and materials.
But Democritos realized that this is not enough to explain the world.
Had atoms been the only thing that existed, change would not have been possible
- This is because the atoms did not then have the opportunity to move.
Therefore, the void between the atoms also plays an important role in theory.
This void is something Aristotle would later call "vacuum".
Today's modern atomic theory originates from British chemist John Dalton and the beginning of the 19th century.
Democritos atoms are most recently reminiscent of what we today call molecules
- Thus, a set of atoms that together create a Ting's characteristics.